New York State Board of Mediation Case Files 5103
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State Board of Mediation Case Files
1928-1960
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State Board of Mediation
5103
4.5 cubic feet
4.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
In June 1806, the legislature of the State of New York enacted legislation, chapter 410 of the Laws of the State of New York, to provide for the amicable adjustment of grievances and disputes that may arise between employers and employees, and to authorize the creation of a State Board of Arbitration. In March 1887, the legislature enacted legislation, chapter 63, of the Laws of the State of New York, to provide for the amicable adjustment of grievances and disputes that may arise between employers and employees, and to authorize the creation of a State Board of Mediation and Arbitration. Since then, there have been surprisingly few major changes in the actual procedures of mediating and arbitrating labor disputes, although the form of the agency has undergone several transformations. The present Board was established in 1937 by act of the legislature. The provisions of the act constitute article 21 of the Labor Law of New York State. Section 750 sets forth the purpose and function of the Board of Mediation in a "declaration of policy." This section also establishes the Board and provides for a membership of seven persons to be appointed by the Governor by and with the advice of the Senate. The Board shall be within the Department of Labor. Section 752 defines the Board's objective as to "take such steps as will most effectively and expeditiously carry out the policy declared in Section 750." Section 753 delineates the powers and duties of the Board. It provides that upon its own motion, in an existing, imminent or threatened labor dispute, the Board may, and, upon the direction of the Governor, the board must take such steps as it may deem expedient to effect and voluntary amicable and expeditious adjustment and settlement of the differences and issues between employer and employees which have precipitated or culminated in or threat to precipitate or culminate in such labor disputes. In 1941, article 22 was added to the Labor Laws of New York State. It provides for the creation of a Board of Inquiry by the Industrial Commissioner in the event the mediation Board certifies to him that it has been unsuccessful in its attempts to effect and voluntary settlement of a dispute. In terms of the functional pyramid, the open of the Board's formal organization is composed of seven Board members, appointed by the Governor. Beneath them, and appointed by the Board are two administrative offices, the Executive Secretary, and his assistant. They are charged with the responsibility of supervising day-to-day functions and meeting the numerous operating problems. A third appointee of the Board is the Counsel, who gives legal advice and assistance to the Board's members administrative officers are "four supervising labor mediators, one each located in New York City, Albany, Buffalo, and Syracuse. They are in charge of a staff of full time labor mediators distributed according to the needs of the agency among the four offices, and stenographer and clerks. There are 12 full time mediators employed by the Board; 2 in Buffalo, 1 in Syracuse, 3 in Albany, and 6 in New York City. In addition, panel lists of 100 persons are available to the Board for use in the designation of arbitrators. The Board and its personnel intervene in labor disputes at the request of the parties or on its own motion to assist them in minimizing economic losses arising from threatened by industrial disputes, and in improving the relations between employer and unions. These services take the form of either mediation or voluntary arbitration. Mediation Cases are classified as follows: Work Stoppage a.Not contrary to agreement. This means an actual cessation of work not expressly prohibited by agreement. B. Contrary to agreement. An actual cessation of work prohibited by agreement. No Work Stoppage a. Authorization for Strike. The union has specifically-authorized a strike. B. Threat of Strike. When there exists a strike threat although a strike was not specifically authorized. C. No Stoppage Threatened. Where there is no actual cessation of work, no authorization or threat of strike (i.e. an agreement not to strike or to arbitrate if mediation flails.) Arbitration Cases arise when: a. Dispute arises over the initial contract; or b. Over the renewal of a contract, or c. During the life of the contract. The State mediators cooperate with other agencies in a number of critical or protracted disputes, for example, representatives of the New York State Board of Mediation in some instances joined with Federal or New York City mediators in intensive mediation efforts. The Board of Mediation also drafts the services of individual within communities to supplement the efforts of Board personnel. The New York State Board of Mediation has been frequently designated as the arbitrating authority in collective bargaining contracts by agreement between the parties. Although the staff mediators have the official title of mediators, they are also required to be qualified as arbitrators. They are the basic resource for the unique service of free arbitration furnished by the State. The law establishes the Board of Mediation in the Department of Labor. At the head of this department is the Industrial Commissioner. Since 1902, the body designated to mediate and arbitrate labor disputes has been under the supervision of the Industrial Commissioner. Between 1886 and 1902 it was independent. The relationship is more one of partnership and cooperation than subordination, for the Board's responsibility is directly to the Governor and tangentially to the Industrial Commissioner. The records of the New York State Board of Mediation are compiled in boxes, each box containing the record of one year. When an application is made to the Board either by the employer or the labor organization or by both, requesting the assistance of the board either by way of mediation, arbitration or otherwise, in an effort to resolve a current labor dispute, a file is made and all materials concerning this dispute are contained in this file. For purposes of convenience and in an attempt to save time and money, a survey was made of the record for the years, 1938, 1945, 1949, 1952 and 1962. These years were chosen for the following reasons: 1949 1 Several disputes arose as to the employer's quantum/ of contribution to the union's welfare, health and security plans and the union Insurance funds. 2. Several disputes arose out of the alleged union's rights to compel the employers to dismiss employees who have not or are not members of the union in good standing. 3. Unlike the 1938 and to a lesser extent the 1945 period, the vast majority of matters submitted to arbitration were determined by the arbitrator. There were no amicable settlement of the issues. 1952 1. This period continued in roughly the same way as that of 1949 with no departure that is of any real significance to note. 1960 1. Employers secured the right to lay off employees if business should fail and several disputes arose as to whether business had failed or not. 2. The question of seniority ratings was also disputed on several occasions. 3. Apart from these areas the basic questions as before re mained. As explained earlier, these cases that have been examined and made the subject matter of this report are only random samples picked from various periods. A complete list of all cases is available for a comprehensive study.
3117209
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 09, 2015
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 28, 2016
Biographical / Historical
In June 1806, the legislature of the State of New York enacted legislation, chapter 410 of the Laws of the State of New York, to provide for the amicable adjustment of grievances and disputes that may arise between employers and employees, and to authorize the creation of a State Board of Arbitration. In March 1887, the legislature enacted legislation, chapter 63, of the Laws of the State of New York, to provide for the amicable adjustment of grievances and disputes that may arise between employers and employees, and to authorize the creation of a State Board of Mediation and Arbitration.
Since then, there have been surprisingly few major changes in the actual procedures of mediating and arbitrating labor disputes, although the form of the agency has undergone several transformations. The present Board was established in 1937 by act of the legislature. The provisions of the act constitute article 21 of the Labor Law of New York State. Section 750 sets forth the purpose and function of the Board of Mediation in a "declaration of policy." This section also establishes the Board and provides for a membership of seven persons to be appointed by the Governor by and with the advice of the Senate. The Board shall be within the Department of Labor. Section 752 defines the Board's objective as to "take such steps as will most effectively and expeditiously carry out the policy declared in Section 750." Section 753 delineates the powers and duties of the Board. It provides that upon its own motion, in an existing, imminent or threatened labor dispute, the Board may, and, upon the direction of the Governor, the board must take such steps as it may deem expedient to effect and voluntary amicable and expeditious adjustment and settlement of the differences and issues between employer and employees which have precipitated or culminated in or threat to precipitate or culminate in such labor disputes.
In 1941, article 22 was added to the Labor Laws of New York State. It provides for the creation of a Board of Inquiry by the Industrial Commissioner in the event the mediation Board certifies to him that it has been unsuccessful in its attempts to effect and voluntary settlement of a dispute.
In terms of the functional pyramid, the open of the Board's formal organization is composed of seven Board members, appointed by the Governor. Beneath them, and appointed by the Board are two administrative offices, the Executive Secretary, and his assistant. They are charged with the responsibility of supervising day-to-day functions and meeting the numerous operating problems. A third appointee of the Board is the Counsel, who gives legal advice and assistance to the Board's members administrative officers are "four supervising labor mediators, one each located in New York City, Albany, Buffalo, and Syracuse. They are in charge of a staff of full time labor mediators distributed according to the needs of the agency among the four offices, and stenographer and clerks. There are 12 full time mediators employed by the Board; 2 in Buffalo, 1 in Syracuse, 3 in Albany, and 6 in New York City. In addition, panel lists of 100 persons are available to the Board for use in the designation of arbitrators.
The Board and its personnel intervene in labor disputes at the request of the parties or on its own motion to assist them in minimizing economic losses arising from threatened by industrial disputes, and in improving the relations between employer and unions. These services take the form of either mediation or voluntary arbitration.
Mediation Cases are classified as follows:
Work Stoppage
a. Not contrary to agreement. This means an actual cessation of work not expressly prohibited by agreement.
b. Contrary to agreement. An actual cessation of work prohibited by agreement.
No Work Stoppage
a. Authorization for Strike. The union has specifically-authorized a strike.
b. Threat of Strike. When there exists a strike threat although a strike was not specifically authorized.
c. No Stoppage Threatened. Where there is no actual cessation of work, no authorization or threat of strike (i.e. an agreement not to strike or to arbitrate if mediation flails.)
Arbitration Cases arise when:
a. Dispute arises over the initial contract; or
b. Over the renewal of a contract, or
c. During the life of the contract.
The State mediators cooperate with other agencies in a number of critical or protracted disputes, for example, representatives of the New York State Board of Mediation in some instances joined with Federal or New York City mediators in intensive mediation efforts. The Board of Mediation also drafts the services of individual within communities to supplement the efforts of Board personnel. The New York State Board of Mediation has been frequently designated as the arbitrating authority in collective bargaining contracts by agreement between the parties.
Although the staff mediators have the official title of mediators, they are also required to be qualified as arbitrators. They are the basic resource for the unique service of free arbitration furnished by the State.
The law establishes the Board of Mediation in the Department of Labor. At the head of this department is the Industrial Commissioner. Since 1902, the body designated to mediate and arbitrate labor disputes has been under the supervision of the Industrial Commissioner. Between 1886 and 1902 it was independent. The relationship is more one of partnership and cooperation than subordination, for the Board's responsibility is directly to the Governor and tangentially to the Industrial Commissioner.
Scope and Contents
The records of the New York State Board of Mediation are compiled in boxes, each box containing the record of one year. When an application is made to the Board either by the employer or the labor organization or by both, requesting the assistance of the board either by way of mediation, arbitration or otherwise, in an effort to resolve a current labor dispute, a file is made and all materials concerning this dispute are contained in this file.
For purposes of convenience and in an attempt to save time and money, a survey was made of the record for the years, 1938, 1945, 1949, 1952 and 1962. These years were chosen for the following reasons:
1949
1. Several disputes arose as to the employer's quantum/ of contribution to the union's welfare, health and security plans and the union Insurance funds.
2. Several disputes arose out of the alleged union's rights to compel the employers to dismiss employees who have not or are not members of the union in good standing.
3. Unlike the 1938 and to a lesser extent the 1945 period, the vast majority of matters submitted to arbitration were determined by the arbitrator. There were no amicable settlements of the issues.
1952
1. This period continued in roughly the same way as that of 1949 with no departure that is of any real significance to note.
1960
1. Employers secured the right to lay off employees if business should fail and several disputes arose as to whether business had failed or not.
2. The question of seniority ratings was also disputed on several occasions.
3. Apart from these areas the basic questions as before remained.
As explained earlier, these cases that have been examined and made the subject matter of this report are only random samples picked from various periods. A complete list of all cases is available for a comprehensive study.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5581: New York State Board of Mediation Cases
Mediation and conciliation, Industrial--New York (State)--Sources.; Arbitration, Industrial--New York (State)--Sources.
3117209
- New York Arbitration Cases, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- New York State Labor Agreements, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Arbitration Agreements, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  New York State
- A60-519 Laboratory Furniture Co., Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- A60-540 Oceana International Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- A60-547 Universal Utilities, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- A60-553 Waljohn Plastics, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- A60-591 Lee Filter Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- A60-630 \ Envelope, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- A60-699 John Bivona Carting Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- A60-516 Industrial Plywood, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- A60-568 Boro Lumber Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- A60-698 Bayside Carting, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- A60-697 Armo Carting Co., Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- A60-694 52 West 117th Street, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- A60-693 2167 Crotona Avenue, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- A60-691 J. Ossola & Company, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- A60-690 Samson Lighting Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- A60-686 Dugan Brothers, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- A60-683 Wantagh Hotel, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- A60-679 Imperial Handle Mfg. Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- A60-677 Black Angus Restaurant, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- A60-675 Atlantic Gummed Paper Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- A60-673 Allen-Stevens Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- A60-670 Mutual Maintenance Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- A60-669 Sleepnite Bedding Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- A60-663 Nathan Bulos et al, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- A60-661 Crawford Clothes Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- A60-660 Brooklyn Doctors Hospital, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- A60-659 Art Award Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- A60-658 Ford Instrument, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- A60-657 Crown Novelty Works, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- A60- 656 Baden & Foss, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- A60-652 Fisher-Stevens Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- A60-651 Individual Rug Cleaners Assn., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- A60-648 "The" Barber Shop, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- A60-645 United Transformer Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- A60-642 United Crayon, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- A60-641 Quartite Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- A60-637 L. C. Bigelow and Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- A60-636 Bellis Wire Works, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- A60-635 Barricini, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- A60-634 Raybern Bus Service, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- A60-632 Amra Wrecking Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- A60-631 Retail Credit Bureau, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- A60-622 North River Meat Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- A60-621 200 West 145 St., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- A60-620 Berkley Barber Shop, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- A60-619 Fisk Building Barber Shop, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- A60-618 Arcade Barber Shop, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- A60-617 110-50 71 Road, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- A60-613 Allied Maintenance Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- A60-612 S. B. Thomas, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- A60-611 Hauptman Feather Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- A60-608 1219 Union Ave., BX., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- A60-607 458 Brook Ave., BX., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- A60-602 Detra Watchcase Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- A60-600 Barrows Chemical Co., Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- A60-598 Albano Co., Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- A60-597 Bilt-Rite Baby Carriage, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- A60-596 Structural Steel Processing, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- A60-595 Lew Morris Demolition Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- A60-589 Gordon Baking Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- A60-586 Art Aware Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- A60-584 Seasonmaster Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- A60-583 Oscar Heineman Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- A60-582 H. A. Enrich Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- A60-578 Himoff Machine Company, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- A60-573 Rainbow Children's Wear, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- A60-572 1521-23 Washington Ave., BX., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- A60-567 Abbro Metallics, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- A60-566 Peerless Mailing Service, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- A60-562 C. Richard Ferris, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- A60-561 Allied Drapery Company, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- A60-558 H. Barrows, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- A60-551 Himoff Machine Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- A60-549 Woodlux, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- A60-548 Cutting Room Appliances, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- A60-546 Republic Plating, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- A60-536 Almax Sportswear Company, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- A60-532 Fisher Stevens, Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- A60-530 1827-29 Washington Avenue, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- A60-527 Empire Extrusions Corp., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- A60-523 H. A. Johnson Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- A60-522 Eldine MFG. Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- A60-520 D & S Paper & Twine, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 83)
- A60-515 Garwood Ind. Inc., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- Al-540 Hawley & Hoops, Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Al-305 Lubin's Bar & Grill, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Al-306 Hudson Box Spring & Mattress Box Company, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Al-307 NY Air Valve Corporation, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Al-309 Club Transportation Corp., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Al-310 Allied Maintenance Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Al-313 Julius Blackman Corp., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Al-319 Stanley Gowns, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Al-321 555-557 Timpson Place, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Al-323 2420 Grand Avenue, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Al-326 1665 Weeks Avenue, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Al-331 Aljack Luncheonette, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Al-332 C & W Restaurant, Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Al-333 Gilman Pharmacy, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Al-335 Simon Manufacturing Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Al-336 Metropolitan Funeral Directors Assn. Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Al-337 1504-1530 Sheridan Ave., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Al-340 Ardsley Novelty Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Al-341 501 West 170th St., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Al-342 G. M. Ketcham Mfg. Corp., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Al-347 2775 Kingsbridge Terrace, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Al-348 Hardman, Peck & Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Al-351 Tri-Boro Coach Corporation, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Al-353 National Moulded and National Electro Plating Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Al-360 39 Marcy Place, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Al-362 1371 Shakespeare Ave., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Al-365 1016 50th Street, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Al-368 71 Ocean Parkway, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Al-369 Janugs Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Al-376 Hobart Sales Co. Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Al- 377 Wilrose Dress Shop, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Al-381 A. De Pinna Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Al-383 408-420 West 148th Street, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Al-386 Brooklyn Mattress Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Al-387 Concord Operating, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Al-388 Gottfried Baking Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Al-389 Roman Silversmiths, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Al-390 General Bronze, Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Al-396 Drasner Spring Co, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Al-403 9502 Kings Highway, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Al-418 Lion Machine Corp., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Al-443 Crosley Distributing Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Al-445 Metro Photo Service, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Al-424 Metro Sacks Co., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Al-425 Loral Electronics, Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Al-429 289 Convent Avenue, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Al-430 Allied Display Materials, Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Al-431 Superior Meter Co., Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Al-440 Shunt Lamp Corporation, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Al-451 National Piano Corporation, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Al-446 Book Publishers Shipping Service, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Al-421 Exel Foods, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Al-452 2400 Seventh Avenue, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Al-453 Yonkers Cabinet Corporation, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Al-455 Lewis & Conger, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Al-457 Royal Rest Company, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 56)